# Curriculum Vitae - Everton Canez F. da Silva

Everton Canez - everton.canez@gmail.com - Version 4.5, Oct 2019

# **Timeline**

1997	1998	2000	2001	2005	2011	2015 - present
<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li></ul>	<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>ASP</li><li>3.0</li></ul>	<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>PHP</li></ul>	<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>Java</li><li>PHP</li></ul>	<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>Java</li><li>JSP</li><li>PHP</li></ul>	<ul><li>HTML</li><li>CSS</li><li>JavaScript</li><li>Java</li><li>Android</li></ul>	<ul> <li>HTML</li> <li>CSS</li> <li>JavaScript</li> <li>Java</li> <li>Android</li> <li>lonic</li> <li>Typescript</li> <li>Angular</li> <li>NodeJS</li> </ul>

# **About me**

I'm flexible, easy going style with 18y+ hands-on software development experience and practical experience working with web and mobile projects, using CI/CD to automate building processes with Jenkins and TFS.

I'm very capable of working in any team, I'm skilled, specially in javascript using nodeJs and angular, but I'm also experienced in Android and Java. I like frontend and back-end development, I love programming languages and I'm very committed self-learning person and i'd like to work with a creative team in projects that make difference for the clients business value.

# **Fullstack Developer**

PROCERGS Aug 2011 – Present Porto Alegre Area, Brazil In 2011, after months on the new position as Java Analyst i was invited to join the mobile/web team where I had the opportunity to work with all the tecnologies that surrounds it. My responsibility was research & development for mobile/web projects. It was the early days of mobile platforms so I started another fase of my career. Now i was not only a Java Analyst, Mobile and Web Developer, but a researcher too.

In this position i was able to find other ways to solve software architecture problems, another tecnologies, other ways to think e solve things and in these almost last 9 years on it i was able to work with many different projects wich led me to work with:

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- AngularJS
- Restify
- Express
- NodeJS
- Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...
- UX
- Ionic
- Cordova
- Progressive Web Apps
- RESTful APIs
- Java
- Android
- OOP
- Micro-services

Today i work as a frontend and backend developer with teams in transit department, water and sewage department, police and security, and many others government areas to help improove public services.

# **Professional Experience**

## **Java Analyst**

PROCERGS Aug 2011 - Dec 2011 (4 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil In 2011 i did for a public tender to start at a new position as Java Analyst and i passed to arrume a new position. I started working with Java/PHP/Javascript/HTML/CSS in several intern projects to solve problems for the management area who wanted to automatize some process and workflows in the company using Oracle Workflow and Java.

Some of this workflows were about implementation of ITIL (Information Technology Infrastructure Library), in disciplines like Configuration Management, Changing Management, Problems Management and so on.

## **Web Developer**

**PROCERGS** 

February 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In 2005 I was invited to join the Technical Operations Team. At this point I was beginning with Java/JSP for software development in one project, but in Technical Operations team i was able to work in several other projects. In some point I was responsible for maintaining 6 Java applications simultaneously, all of them communicating with each other via web services (SOAP and after a while RESTful).

By the time it was a common thing the monolithic architecture and so it was for a while. Meanwhile, i was having a good progression on my career being promoted each couple of years or so.

# **Technical Operations Engineer**

**PROCERGS** 

March 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 11 months) Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

In March 2000, i became a team member of the Systems Operations Department as Technical Specialist and i was responsible for developing web systems for the company's intranet. By then i used to program a lot in ASP and had to learn more about data modelling and some Systems Analysis, providing a huge workflow for this department I was working in.

# **System Network Administrator**

Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário Porto Alegre e Região, Brasil August 1998 - July 2001 (3 years)

Porto Alegre Area, Brazil Responsible for the IT support for school's intranet, network and website development

# **Call Center Agent**

**PROCERGS** 

December 1997 - March 2000 (2 years 4 months) Porto Alegre e Região, Brazil

Call center attendant responsible IT support for clients of several areas like Police Department, Public Security, Water and Sewage Department and Company's Internet Provider clients.

# **Education**

#### 2014 - 2016

Graduate course Computer Software Engineering Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2007 - 2010

University graduate Computer Software Technology/Technician Faculdade de Tecnologia SENAC-RS

# **Main Interests**

- Javascript
- Angular
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- Open Source
- UX
- APIs
- Microservices
- Android
- Java

# **Soft Skills**

- Committed
- Creative
- Passionate
- Proactive
- Productive
- Empathy
- Active listening
- Adaptable
- Business focused
- Enthusiastic
- Collaborative

# **Personal Details**

Nome: Everton Canez Ferreira da Silva

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Social Media: @notreniev, notreniev.github.com

Calendly https://calendly.com/evcanez

**Skype:** everton.canez@gmail.com **Phone:** Phone: +55 51 991120621

## **Portfolio**

#### Randonneurs Brazil

This is a freelance and the latest project i'm still working on among other things. It consists in a **NodeJS** backend persisting in a **MySQL** database for Randonneurs Brazil, wich is an organization that regulates and approves brevets randonneurs mondiaux, the BRMs, linked to the Audax Club Parisien of ciclism. This backend will attend an **Angular** website and a React Native app.

#### **BMMOB**

An App to help police from Rio Grande do Sul State to attend daily police reports. It was written in **Ionic Framework** with **Cordova** to run in **Android** devices. This app comnunicates with a **Java** (1.8) backend on **JBoss Server 7.0** to sinchronize its data with several informations and photos of this reports with an **Oracle Database**.

#### **National Address Consulting**

This is a **microservice** writen in **Java** for integration with other Government applications for consuming address in Brazil as a **Java Rest API**. It helps to locate address information in the whole country based on zip code, address, city or state. This **API** was develop using **Java 1.8** running in a cluster of **Jboss Server 6.4** and **Oracle 10** Database.

## **PROCERGS Apps**

This is an internal app store for PROCERGS company to distribute apps for clients who doesn't want to distribute their apps through oficial app stores like Google or Apple. It was written using AngularJS in Front-end, communicating with Java 1.8 REST API on back-end, and persisting its data in a PostgreSQL Database.

## **Digital School**

Project in partnership with Pontifical Catholic University (PUCRS) and Huawei to informatize school classroom processes in public schools of State of Rio Grande do Sul. Consists in sinchronize classroom information through a mobile app running in a **Android** tablet an then sending all information to a **Jboss server REST API** in the backend with an **Oracle Database**.

#### **Turismo RS**

This is an **Android** app for Tourism in the Rio Grande do Sul state. It gives information about the cities, touristic points of interest, places to stay, places to eat, hotels and etc. It communicates with an PHP back-end.

#### Offline ballot box

The popular offline ballot box is an **Android** app that consists of an electronic ballot box app to vote on citizen budget priorities, and it's persisted on a PHP back-end API using a **PostgreSQL**. Its goal is to bring popular voting to areas without internet access, allowing more citizens to participate on the voting process to prioritise projects on public sector.

#### **Voice List**

This is an **Android** app briefly inspired by the GTD (Getting Things Done) concept. It's a personal project wich allow users to create organised lists using their voice and manage those lists to manage tasks, prioritising between active and archived lists and also marking list items as being finished.

## **52 Weeks Challenge**

This is also a personal project writen in **Android** to help users to save money. The goal here is to save a small amount of money every week always doubling this small quantity each week until you get the amount you need to achieve your goals.

# **Technical Skills**

## **Languages and Framworks:**

- Javascript
- Typescript
- Angular
- NodeJS
- Restify
- Express
- Jest
- Java
- Spring Boot
- Android
- Shell script

#### **Databases:**

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB
- SQLite
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL

OS: OSX, Windows

#### Tools:

- VSCode
- Eclipse
- Git
- Bash Shell
- Gradle
- Netbeans
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Spring Tools Suite
- Jenkins
- Artifactory

# Language Skills

• Portuguese: Native language

• English: Fluent

# **Personal Interests**

- My family: Father of a little girl and owned by two cats
- Music: Playing guitar, blues, rock, Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin, AC/DC
- Movies: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, Back to the Future
- **Books:** Lord of The Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien, Eric Clapton Biography by Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin Biography by Mick Wall
- TV Shows: The Big Bang Theory, Stranger Things, Brooklin 99, La Casa de Papel
- Programming: Frontend, UX and Backend Development
- Sports: Running, bicycle, swimming

Version 4.5 Last update 2019-10-12 17:40